# Puja Maharjan

**Artist** 

9863604372

maharjanpuja55@gmail.com

🖸 Changragiri-14 , Kathmandu

## **SUMMARY**

Puja Maharjan is an art student studied in the 'Lalitkala Campus' of fine arts. She is fond of the open spaces and the aesthetics of everyday objects and likes to paint them. She has grown up being close to the local traditions, the culture, and the artistic practice that goes along with it. She has been fascinated by the stories the objects that belong to her and the space she lives in have a lot to tell. The object and space are manipulated by human activities. The close inspection of the object and the spaces has let her connect to the distant past and reflect on the personal and communal history. She wishes to translate those experiences into an art form. For her practice as an art learner, she is doing more representative and study works, at the same time making efforts to conceptualize them with her understanding. She has shown her participation in the workshops and the Competitions and student-level exhibitions.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# **EDUCATION**

#### **SEE**

Motherland Secondary School / Kathmandu / April, 2024 - April, 2024

#### +2

Universal College / Kathmandu / April, 2024 - April, 2024

Fine Arts

## **Bachelors in Fine Arts**

Lalitkala Campus / Kathmandu / April, 2024 - April, 2024

## **AWARDS**

#### **First Place**

Nepal Public Health Foundation / 2022 / Baluwatar

Art Competition organized by Nepal Public Health Foundation on "Pesticides and Human Health".

## **Second Position**

Nepal Lalitkala Manch / 2012 / Bhotahity

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Art Teacher**

Motherland Secondary School / Chandragiri-14 / April, 2017 - Present

## **Venue Coordinator**

Siddhartha Art Foundation / Maligaun-5 / December, 2021 - April, 2022

For Kathmandu Triennale

# **Administrative Assistant (Fine Arts Department)**

Universal College / Maitidevi / May, 2022 - April, 2024

## **Art Teacher**

Bright Future Secondary School / Changragiri-14 / May, 2022 - Present